MAURO DONEDA

London Area, UK | M: 07534 154055

| mauro.doneda@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/maurodoneda | github.com/maurodoneda

About

I'm a Full Stack Software Developer with a background in Engineering and Finance. I'm passionate about coding and currently I can code in C#/.Net, HTML/CSS, JavaScript and SQL, all following OOP principles. I love to learn new things and my approach to life is: No challenge is too big. Each time you fall you get up stronger! I have a STEM degree: Masters in Mechanical Engineering, and a Masters degree in Financial Markets. My background comprises of 4 years of experience working for big Multinational companies in the heavy industry and 4 years trading the stock markets for a proprietary trading desk and independently.

- Check my personal website at <u>maurodoneda.com</u> and see some of my <u>Projects</u>

Personal Projects

- Movies Database WebApp An Interactive movie search webapp where you can query through any movie that you would like to watch, see its trailer and add to your own watchlist.
 Tech used: HTML5 / CSS3 / JavaScript / Youtube API / JSON and AJAX
- Supercar Experience WebApp A webapp that you can look details of supercars and select one of them to book a supercar experience in one of the cities available.
 Tech used: .Net/ ASP.Net MVC-5 / C# /EntityFramework-6/ SQL-Server / Javascript / Bootstrap4 and CSS3
- **Chess Game** A console chess game you can play using your keyboard. Built using Object Oriented Program paradigm.

Tech used: C# /.NetCore / OOP

Skills

Technologies

- C.#
- .Net Core
- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- React
- MySQL and SQLServer

Tools and Methodologies

- Visual Studio
- VS Code
- Command Line
- Git
- JSON
- SOLID
- Object Oriented Programing

Soft Skills

- Empathy
- Proactivity
- Good Comunicator
- Grit
- Quick Learner
- Logical Thinking
- Team Oriented
- Creative

Experience

DEVELOPMENT PROFESSIONAL PROGRAMME

Jan 2020 - Current

Self-Funded Program - Just It - London, UK

 Joined a self-funded presential course where I studied and used the latest tools and technologies for development together with a small group of learners.

- Used Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code to create front-end apps with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.
- Used coding best-practices with C# and .Net to create small console applications.
- Created Full-Stack apps using ASP.Net MVC, Entity Framework6 and MS SQL Server.

STOCKS AND FUTURES TRADER

Jan 2016 to Jan 2020

Self-Employed - Sao Paulo, Brazil

- Perform short term operations in the Brazilian stock market using Order Flow Analysis,
 Price Action, and Dow Theory in order to make a profit.
- Utilized Risk and Statistical analysis for options trading.
- Returned 385% in 2019 Net Profit on day trade strategies and 119% on Options strategies.

FINANCIAL ANALYST

Jan 2013 to Jul 2014

Votorantim Metals - Sao Paulo, Brazil

- Created several reports focusing on working capital KPIs and Cash Flow improvements.
- Planned and executed financial Working Capital Committees with the company's VPs through 2013 and 2014.
- Helped the implementation of the first BI automated report alongside holding controllers.
- Delivered a marketing project as part of the implementation of the MES automated system in all factories, presented to the board of directors in the training academy.
- Reviewed and provided comments on the adequacy of documents and took necessary steps to cure any deficiencies.
- Prepared budgets, forecasts and financial reports for analysis.
- Monitored multiple databases to keep track of the company's working capital variations.

PRODUCT SUPORT ANALYST

Apr 2011 to Jan 2013

Volvo Group(Contractor) - Curitiba, Brazil

- Spare Parts catalogue creation for Volvo Truck and Buses
- Analyse 3D models in order to correctly indicate spare parts to truck dealers around Latin
- America Participate in 9 different projects of Trucks and Buses launching in 2011 and 2012

Education

Masters, Financial Markets

Mar 2012 to May 2014

FAE Business School – Curitiba

- Related coursework: Macroeconomy, Stock Markets, Strategic Planning, Financial Math, Risk Analysis.

Master of Engineering, Mechanical Engineering

Aug 2005 to Aug 2011

Federal University of Parana - Curitiba

- Related coursework: Project Management, Programming, Calculus, Linear Algebra, Advanced Maths, Physics, Thermodynamics, Fluid Mechanics, Vibrations Theory, Materials, Metallurgy, Product Design and Development.

Spoken Languages

Portuguese | English | Spanish | Italian

Interests

Trading | Sports | Traveling | Cinema | Reading | Cooking